田坤

电话: (+86)13651276832/(+1)443.824.3257 • Email: kuntian0214@gmail.com

地 址: 北京市海淀区成府路 20 号眷 42 楼



个人简介

约翰霍普金斯大学金融硕士项目毕业生,有丰富的金融知识和财务工作经验,有创新精神,团队合作精神,并能以独特的视角成功分析和解决问题,有责任心和耐心,熟悉 US.GAAP, IFRS 和中国会计准则,熟练运用 Excel,MATLAB 软件等进行财务数据分析及建模。

教育经历

约翰霍普金斯大学,硕士学位 金融专业

2013年8月-2014年8月

相关课程:金融建模,风险管理,衍生品,对冲基金投资,固定收益,数理财务分析等

GPA: 3.24

首都经济贸易大学, 学士学位 会计专业

2008年9月-2012年7月

相关课程: 财务会计,财务管理,成本管理会计,税法,高级会计,财务报表分析,审计

GPA: 3.65, GMAT: 690

波士顿大学,交换生项目

2011年8月-2011年12月

相关课程: 投资分析和投资组合管理, 个人理财规划, 中级财务管理

GPA: 3.74

项目经验

约翰霍普金斯行业研究社团,华盛顿,美国

2013年10月-2014年8月

行研培训部副部长,约翰霍普金斯大学

- 通过电话会议对各种公司和股票进行行业分析及行业研究
- 在有经验人士的带领下学习对股票的基本面分析和数理分析
- 完成行业研究分析报告并且深化对相关产业的知识和分析技术

对冲基金投资项目,巴尔的摩,美国

2014年6月-2014年8月

项目负责人,约翰霍普金斯大学

- 在证券市场上利用统计套利方法设计和执行交易策略规则
- 依据条件对证券市场和新兴国家证券市场上股票进行筛选
- 评估投资策略的表现和风险,并对其进行改进:增加动态交易,高频交易等特性

工作经验

诺华制药有限公司,北京

2012年7月-2013年4月

财务分析员, 财务部

- 根据折扣递减制度计算和发放经销商补偿:包括招标补偿,回款返利,降价补偿等
- 利用 excel 和 vba 宏辅助编制价格矩阵
- 导入和维护各项折扣递减数据
- 辅助编制收入扣除报告和保管折扣递减证明资料文件
- 与内部外部客户沟通提高客户对于销售回扣计算和处理的满意度

中华人民共和国商务部

2012年4月-2012年6月

内审实习生, 财务司审计处

- 负责组织对事务所的招标工作
- 参与下属组织学会领导人的经济责任审计,负责财政拨款专项资金的项目审计
- 配合审计署贸易审计局在商务部的各项审计工作,与各司各处协调沟通配合审计工作,索要审计支持文件材料。

德勤会计师事务所,北京

2012年2月-2012年3月

审计实习生, 审计二组

- 参与中铁集团年终财务报表审计,与客户维持良好的关系,使审计过程顺利进行
- 负责银行函证,往来函证的选样和收发以及存货减值测试
- 在有限的时间内成功解决数据不全等问题,改变抽样计划,使现金部分审计任务能按时达标完成

附加信息

专业技术:会计,财务建模,投资组合管理,对冲投资,风险管理

计算机技术: 全国计算机等级考试二级,熟练使用 MATLAB, Excel, MS Office, SAP, Bloomberg Data System 等软件

英语水平: 大学英语六级(577分), 托福(106分/120分);

专业测试: Bloomberg Aptitude Test: 75%

Kun Tian

25 River Dr S, Apt 903, Jersey City, NJ 07310 • (443)824-3257 • kuntian0214@gmail.com

Profile

Kun Tian graduated from Master of Science in Finance program from the Johns Hopkins University. She has strong logic thinking demonstrated through past working experience and case studies. She is also proficient in financial analysis developed through building models using MS Excel and MATLAB. She is interested in future internship/full-time job opportunity in the related areas of asset management and trading in North America and Asia.

Education

Master of Science, Finance, Johns Hopkins University

Aug 2014

Relevant Coursework: Financial Modeling, Advanced Hedge Fund Strategy, Fixed Income, Derivatives, etc.

GPA: 3.24

Bachelor of Accounting, Capital University of Economics and Business

Jul 2012

Relevant Coursework: Financial Accounting, Corporate Finance, Advanced Accounting, Taxation, etc.

GPA: 3.65 GMAT: 690

Exchange Student Program, Boston University

Aug 2011-Dec 2011

Finance Courses: Investment Analysis and Portfolio Management, Personal Finance, Financial Management

GPA: 3.74

Program Experience

Vice President of Education, Johns Hopkins Equity Research Team

Oct 2013-Aug 2014

Johns Hopkins University Carey Business School, Washington D.C. Metro Area

- · Conducted conference calls, industry analysis and equity research on various stocks and firms
- Trained on fundamental, quantitative and technical equity analysis under the instruction of experienced professional
- · Prepared equity research reports and deepen the knowledge about related industries and reinforced equity analysis skills

Team Leader, Hedge Fund Trading Strategy Project

Jun 2014-Aug 2014

Johns Hopkins University Carey Business School, Baltimore, Maryland Area

- Used statistic arbitrage to modify and execute trading strategies on equity market
- Conducted screening process on US and emerging markets by selected criteria
- · Evaluated performance and risk of different strategies and implemented them with dynamic high-frequency trading features

Professional Experience

Financial Analyst, Finance and Accounting Department

Jul 2012-Apr 2013

Novartis Pharma Co. Ltd, Beijing

- Calculated and distributed revenue deduction for hospitals and distributors: bidding compensation, cash discount, price-cut
 compensation, etc.
- · Supported price matrix calculations using excel functions and macros
- Transferred old data to new data system and make sure it ran correctly
- · Supported revenue deduction reporting and maintained documentation per internal control requirements
- Improved the customer (internal/external) satisfaction rates for actual revenue deduction in communication and reconciliation process.

Intern, Internal Auditor, Finance Bureau

Apr 2012-Jun 2012

Ministry of Commerce, People's Republic of China

- · Managed bidding process: selected accounting firms and ensured that all the bidding procedures were fair and legal
- Participated in the subordinate organization society leaders economic responsibility auditing, and participate in auditing and tracking process of project using fiscal funds
- Collaborated with National Audit Officers in their auditing program in Ministry of Commerce to develop strong relationships between national auditors and officers in Ministry of Commerce in order to make auditing process going smoothly

Intern, Auditing Department

Feb 2012-Mar 2012

Deloitte, Beijing

- · Implemented annual audit for China Railway Group and handled multiple tasks
- · Successfully maintained a good relationship with client personnel
- · Participated in the cash and bank section and provided support for other colleagues, e.g. documentations, cast, review audit report

Additional Information

Skills: accounting, financial modeling, portfolio management, hedging, risk management **Computer Skills:** MATLAB, MS Office, Access, SAP, Bloomberg Data System

Languages: Chinese: Mandarin (First language); English: TOEFL (106 out of 120)